《僵尸国度》前情提要
Previously on Z Nation.
他们看上去可不像志愿者啊
They don't look like volunteers to me.
成千上万的人不明原因的死去
Millions of people are dying for no reason.
这些人的死会帮助我们找到疫苗
These men are gonna die to help us find a vaccine.
不  不  不  不  不要啊
No, no, no, no, no, no! No, no, no, no!
这些都是僵尸咬的
Those are zombie bites.
八个僵尸
Eight of them.
如果我们能把他送到加利福尼亚的实验室
If we can get him to the lab in California,
他们就能用他的血造出更多抗体
they can use his blood and make more of the vaccine.
他们不会攻击我因为他们爱我敬我
They will not attack me because they love and fear me.
我才是你们的救世主
I'm your messiah.
天呐[耶稣]
Jesus.
不是  只是摩菲而已
No, just Murphy.
[纽约市  疫情爆发前四年]
孩子多大了
How old?
五个月
Five months.
一个完整的人生正等待着他呢
He has his whole life ahead of him.
希望在此之前他能小睡一会儿
Well hopefully he's got a nap ahead of him.
这对他而言的确重要
They're important.
是啊  真希望他能明白这一点
Yeah, I wish he understood that.
他只不过不希望错过任何事而已
He doesn't want to miss anything.
祝你拥有完美的一天
Have a great day.
你也是  亲爱的  还有这个小家伙
You too, my dear. And you.
好好生活  年轻人  让我们都为你感到骄傲吧
Have a good life, young man. Make us all proud of you.
你就是那医生吗
You're the doctor?
没错
That's right.
太好了  我是强尼
Cool. I'm Johnny.
大概有十个街区远  你要打的过去吗
It's about ten blocks away. You want to cab it?
今天是美好的一天
It's a beautiful day.
我们走走路吧
Let's take a walk.
上周我在那儿遇到位老哥  桑迪飓风来临时
Had a buddy down there last week when Sandy hit.
他不得不付给出租车司机两千美金逃出镇子
Had to pay a cabbie two grand to get a ride out of town.
他说当时一切都是疯狂  无法无天的
He said it was bananas, lawless.
其实用不着太多手段就能把人逼成野蛮人
Doesn't take much to get people acting like savages.
只要把他们的食物拿走即可
Just take their food away.
没错  老兄
That's it, brotha.
这是个人吃人的世界
Man eat man.
这就是比尔了
That's Bill.
病的连个坛子都踢不倒了
Just can't kick the crock.
邋遢的不像样子
Shit's nasty.
谢了哈
Sweet.
我要问你几个问题  比尔
I'm going to ask you a few questions, Bill.
你上顿饭何时吃的
When was your last meal?
记不清了
I dunno.
大概一礼拜前吧
A week maybe.
有没有觉得自己对光的敏感度迅速提升了
Have you noticed an increased sensitivity to light?
嗯哼
Uh huh.
手脚麻木没感觉
Numbness in your extremities?
你觉得冷吗
Are you cold?
冷的发抖
Freezing.
你会帮助我吗
Are you gonna help me?
事实上
Actually
是你要来帮助我
you're going to help me.
落基山脉西侧某处  疫情爆发第三年
不确定我们还能在一起撑多久
Not sure how much longer we can hold it together.
再有150英里就到了
It's only another 150 miles.
我们有人倒下了  卡桑德拉
We have a man down, Cassandra.
她看上去可不怎么好
She's not looking good.
还有那"包裹"也是
And then there's the package.
额  "包裹"怎么样了
Uh, what about the package?
不太清楚  但是摩菲的行为怪异
Don't know exactly, but Murphy's acting weird.
比以往要怪异的多
More than usual.
新的目的地在哪
Where's this new destination?
在科罗拉多州科林斯堡
It's Fort Collins, Colorado.
加州那边出什么事了
What happened to California?
研究室那边又没影了
Lab's dark again.
也许是好事  你们被重新部署了
Maybe for good. You've been redeployed.
谁下的指令
By whose orders?
我一开始收到了一段电传打字电报信号
Well I started picking up a teletype signal
在民防波段上收到的
on the old civil defense frequency.
我原以为是黑客干的
At first I thought it was a hacker,
后来发现是莫奇医生发的
but turns out it's Doctor Merch.
是的  就是那个给摩菲注射的莫奇医生
Yeah, that Doctor Merch. The one who injected Murphy.
所以现在把摩菲送到科林斯堡
So delivery Murphy to Fort Collins.
莫奇医生会和她的团队一起在那里等你们
Doctor Merch will be there with her team to meet you.
所以不用再去加州了呗
No more California?
科罗拉多就是新的加利福尼亚
Colorado is the new California.
收到
Copy.
感觉好点了吗
Feel better now?
好点了
Yeah, a little bit.
不行  不行  不行
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
你试着放松点
Try to relax.
我们还剩多少汽油
How much gas do we have left?
我不知道  可能还剩半箱吧
I don't know, half a tank or so.
还能再撑150英里吗
Make it 150 miles?
如果都是下坡路的话  没问题
Well if it's mostly downhill.
我们的子弹也所剩无几了
We're real low on ammo too.
梅撒制药股份有限公司
什么事
Yeah?
我们找到一个接收人
We found a taker.
接收什么
For what?
接收你
For you.
那还去不去加州了
What about California?
我们接到新的命令  现在要去一间
New orders. We are headed to
位于柯林斯堡的实验室
a lab in Fort Collins.
柯林斯堡  那里有什么
Fort Collins? What the hell is in Fort Collins?
莫奇医生在那里等你
Dr. Merch is there waiting for you.
莫奇医生  我跟那个婊子可有的聊了
Doctor Merch? Yeah, I got a bone to pick with that bitch.
正是因为这个婊子  你才能活到现在
That bitch is the reason you're still alive.
请给活着下个定义
Define alive.
摩菲老兄
Well, Murphy.
我猜我会想你这个混蛋的
I think I'm gonna miss your sorry ass.
你的好意我心领了
I appreciate the sentiment.
我们一起跋山涉水  老兄
We logged some miles together, brother.
阿门
Amen.
我都开始觉得咱们像一家人了
Starting to feel like a damn family.
你明白我的意思吧
You know what I'm sayin'?
我不太确定之前有没有跟别人讲过
Uh, I...I don't know if I've actually ever said this to anybody before.
不过我...
But I...
我快要把你当成
I almost consider you
朋友了
a friend.
好吧  尽管我一点也不羡慕你
Yeah, I don't envy you though, man.
等我们把你安全送达目的地  世事难料
I mean, hell, once we deliver you, all bets are off.
专家们就会在你身上戳很多很多针
They're gonna have more needles stuck in you than
比老奶奶针线球上的针都多
the damn tomato in grandma's sewing basket.
-不  他们只会抽出我的...  -相信我
- No, they're...they're just gonna take out my... - Oh, trust me,
他们肯定会用某种管子或者刺针
they're gonna have some kind of tube or prod
插进你身上每个孔里  不然我就跟你姓
rammed in every spare orifice, or my name ain't Sally.
你知道吗  我之前插过一次尿管
You know this one time I had a catheter.
老兄  你最好希望他们别往那里下手
Dude, you better hope they don't go that route.
多克
Doc.
怎么了
What?
还有多远
How much further?
我不清楚  大概还有65英里吧
Uh, I don't know, 65 miles or so.
总之
Anyway,
我会想你的  老兄
I'm gonna miss you, dude.
是哦  好的
Yeah, right.
你呢  小万万
How about you, kid?
你有什么打算
What do you got planned?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
我还要再杀6998个僵尸才能凑够一万
Still got 6,998 to go.
我可能会选择休息一段时间
Might take a break for a while though,
然后北上  向寒冷地带进发
head up north somewhere cold.
僵尸在寒冷的地方会没那么活跃
The Zs don't fare too well in the cold.
我自己在寒冷的地方过得也不太好
Yeah, I don't fare too well in the cold myself.
罗伯塔
Roberta?
我没想好呢
Uh, I don't know.
也许向着太阳西坠的方向走
Maybe follow the sun west.
我以前没去过加州
I've never been to California.
你有什么打算  多克
How 'bout you, Doc?
我可能会买一艘小船
Maybe I'll buy a boat
然后环游世界
and sail around the world.
给自己找一座与世隔绝甚至未曾开化的小岛
Find me an island where there's not even a Z in their alphabet.
应该就是这里了
This must be it.
市民Z让我们找一座有卷闸门的金属小屋
Citizen Z said look for a metal shed with a roll up door.
比如我们眼前这个吗
Like this one?
这群僵尸在看什么
What are they all looking at?
我们的入口
Our entrance.
你觉得我们找对地方了吗
You think we're in the right place?
这地方看上去不大
Looks small.
让我看看你的双手
Let me see your hands.
什么
What?
我的手  为什么
My hands, why?
又要检查个人卫生了吗
Is this a hygiene thing again?
让我看看你的双手就好
Just let me see them.
你到底在做什么
What the hell are you doing?
他们要找的是一群
They're looking for a group of civilians
押送囚犯的普通人
transporting a prisoner.
我不想有人误以为你是僵尸
I don't want anyone mistaking you as a zombie.
胡扯
Bullshit.
我救过你们那么多次  你还是不信任我
You don't trust me. After all the times I've saved your ass.
这与是否信任你无关
Trust has got nothing to do with it.
我们已经护送你这么远了  我不想你被误伤
I don't want anyone piking you after we got you this far.
还是快些搞定这一切吧
Let's just get this over with.
摩菲
Murphy!
我们还有多少弹药
How much ammo do we got?
两发
Two bullets.
我有...
I got...
一发
one.
One?
我早说过了
I told ya.
摩菲
Murphy!
怎么了
What?!
你需要我的帮助了吗
Oh, you want my help?!
当然
Sure,
有何不可呢
why not.
别急
Hold your pants on.
跟着我
Follow me.
你怎么知道这样行得通
How do you know?
我不知道行不行得通
I don't.
别
Don't!
别动武器
Don't do it.
好了  快走
All right, quick.
大家搂紧我
Group hug.
什么
What?
照做就是了
Just do it!
你是想活还是想死
You want to live or not?
也许有一天你该学会信任我
Maybe someday you'll learn to trust me.
伙计  但愿没人看到我们这个样子
Man, I hope nobody sees us.
你知道  大灾变之前
You know before the apocalypse,
大群的姑娘们  对我做同样的事呢
I had the same effect on the ladies.
看来这地方已经瘫痪了
Sure doesn't look operational.
外面那些僵尸
All those zombies up there
肯定是想要这里的什么东西
must've wanted something down here.
是啊  但想要什么呢
Yeah, but what?
它们想要的东西一直没变过
Same thing they always want.
大脑
Brains.
不是
No.
是别的什么
Something different.
这里有什么东西像磁铁一样吸引着它们
Something inside is attracting them like a magnet.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
该死的生日快乐
Happy damn birthday.
让我想起了我的五十岁生日
Uh, reminds me of my 50th.
生日快乐  柯什么博士
Happy birthday Doctor Kur...
先到先吃
Dibs on the last rose.
干嘛啦  人家忍不住嘛
What? I can't help it.
那该死的疫苗让我渴望糖分
Damn vaccine makes me crave sugar.
如果你开始渴望大脑了  一定要告诉我
Well if you start craving brains, let me know.
小乖乖们来了
Puppies and kittens.
利比亚西部  埃博拉隔离营驻地  疫情爆发前三年
这里我来接手
I'll take it from here.
不用忍受太久了  孩子
It won't be long now, my child.
放心
Rest.
你要去一个更好的地方了
You are going to a much better place.
摩菲
Murphy.
考虑到现在的情况
Considering the situation...
你怎么做到的
How did you...?
总做普拉提嘛
Pilates.
他们来了
Here they come.
快  我们躲一下
Come on, let's take cover.
第3002只
Three thousand and two.
但愿刚才那个是僵尸
Well I hope that was a zombie.
十一点方向过来了
Incoming at eleven o'clock.
靠你了  孩子  我没子弹了
That's all you, kid. I'm out.
该死
Damn.
没关系  孩子
It's okay, kid.
还记得在密苏里那家超市吗
Remember that time in Missouri at the Piggly Wiggly?
冷冻食物区那次吗
Frozen food section?
伙计们  看着点僵尸好吗
Guys? Zombies.
第3003只
Three thousand and three.
什么声音
What is that?
好像是手机
It sounds like a phone.
在这
Over here.
肯定收到了二十条短信
There must be 20 text messages here.
看来事故发生的时候他在跟他老婆
Looks like he was texting his wife or somebody
或其他人发短信
when it went down.
今天实验室出事了
Something happened at the lab today.
现在不方便说话  我晚点打给你
Can't talk now. I'll call you later.
要很晚才能回家  没告诉原因
Won't be home till late, not telling us why.
我们被隔离了
Putting us under quarantine.
等我知道更多消息就告诉你
Will update when I know anything.
我有点怕  事情不对劲
Starting to get scared, something very wrong.
我们被感染了  可能出不去了
Something infecting us. We might not get out of here.
告诉孩子们  我爱他们
Tell the kids I love them.
什么
What?
这是市民Z刚刚发来的信息
This is a new message here from Citizen Z.
咬痕研究所  如果你们收到这条信息
Operation Bite Mark. If you get this message,
请回复
please respond.
已黑进实验室主机并进行搜索
Hacked and searching lab mainframe.
发现了应该让你知道的文档
Discovered files you should be aware of.
真的很奇怪的东西
Really weird stuff.
找到能运作的电脑  搜索HZN1实验结果
Find working computer. Search HZN1 test results
反斜线  反斜线  代号九级
backslash backslash code name level nine.
密码  "红色死亡"
Password, red death.
密码是什么来着
What was the passcode?
"红色死亡"
Red death.
挺好记的
Catchy.
他们拿动物做实验并不惊奇
Not surprising they were doing animal testing.
但是他们在做什么实验呢
Yeah, but what were they testing?
看看这些录像上面的日期
Look at the date on these videos.
是人类被感染的前一年
It's the year before anybody was infected.
他们怎么会在人类被感染之前
How did they know to be working on a vaccine
就知道要研发疫苗
before anybody was infected.
这是什么
What's this?
就是她
That's her.
那是莫奇医生
That's Doctor Merch.
就是那个贱人把我弄成现在这副德性的
That's the bitch that did this to me.
行了  行了
Okay, okay.
我们再从头来理一遍
Let's start again from the beginning.
莫奇医生  我刚刚才跟你说过
Doctor Merch, I just got through telling you.
-再跟我说一次 -我们只是想帮助你
- Tell me again. - We're just trying to help you.
不要相信她
Don't believe her!
下班之后我脱掉了防护服
I took the suit off after my shift.
什么时候
At what time?
下午三点  我说过了
15, like I said.
然后呢
And then what?
我把制服扔进焚化炉
Tossed it in the incinerator
然后就直接去消毒了
and went straight to decontamination.
等等  倒回去一下
Let's back up a second.
-我们还要说多少次  -当你脱掉防护服时
- How many times are we gonna - When you took off your suit,
你按什么顺序脱掉它们的
in what order did you remove your items?
我根据规定来脱的
I followed protocol.
规定是什么
Which is?
先脱靴子
Boots.
然后解开防护服的拉链
And unzipped my suit.
脱掉防护服
Removed it.
接着摘掉手套
And gloves.
然后呢
And then what?
把东西都丢进焚化炉
Tossed it in the incinerator.
-然后直接去...  -去消毒了
- And went straight to... - To decontamination.
当你处理你的样本时
Did you notice anything different on this day
有没有发现什么异常
when handling your samples?
我一直按照平常的程序操作
I did as I've always done.
我把样本就放回了原处
I left the samples exactly where I found them.
你有没有和实验室里的任何东西发生接触
Did you come in contact with anything in the lab,
任何尖锐到可能刺破你...
anything sharp that could've punctured your...
我跟你说过十遍了
I told you this ten times!
但是肯定出了什么问题
Well something happened.
这是毋庸置疑的
There's no denying it.
当时肯定出事了
Something happened.
消毒警报响了  那就是所谓的出事
The decontamination alarm went off. That's what happened.
没错
That's right.
不  不对
No, but it's wrong.
我们要调查的
That's what needs to be investigated,
正是警报为什么响了
why the alarm went off.
这是我们要搞清楚的问题
That's what we're trying to find out.
是什么样的污染让病菌警报响了
What form of contamination set off the pathogen alarm.
不对  这是个假警报
No. Cause this is a false alarm.
感应器出了问题
The sensor made an error
因为我...  我没有碰过任何东西
because I... I didn't touch anything.
我没有弄破自己的防护服
I didn't puncture my suit.
我绝对没有违规摘下什么护具
I didn't remove any items out of order.
我都是按规定来的
I followed protocol.
我被感染了吗
Am I gonna be sick?
我猜这位道尔老兄下场不太好
Well I'm guessing it didn't end too well for old Doyle here.
谁同意赶紧离开这个地方
Okay, who's for getting out of here right now?
赞成的举手
Show of hands.
很好
Okay.
那就回到外面的末日世界去
It's back out to the apocalypse it is.
任何人哪也不准去
Nobody's going anywhere.
现在不是搞什么狗屁民主的时候
This is not a goddamn democracy.
我们来是找莫奇医生的
We came here to find Doctor Merch,
所以下一步我们就是要找她
and that is exactly what we are going to do.
他说得对
He's right.
如果她在这  我们不能丢下她不管
If she's down here, we just can't leave her.
她仍然是我们得到解药的唯一机会
She is still our only chance at a vaccine.
那好吧
You're right.
我刚才只是想
I just thought we might want to,
怎么说呢
I dunno,
活命
live.
别做梦了  赶紧出发吧
Yeah, well quit your dreaming and let's go.
哈萨克斯坦  塞米巴拉金斯克
疫情爆发前两年
废弃生化武器实验室
政府放弃这些设施的时候
When the government abandoned this facility,
光把插销一拔就走人了
they just pulled plug and walked away.
那俄国人就一点没有
And the Russians did nothing
对生化武器进行什么保护吗
to secure the bio-weapons they left behind?
现在这里是哈萨克斯坦了
This is Kazakhstan now.
干啥啥没钱  连警察都雇不起了
There is no money for anything, not even pay policemen.
那些被用来测试的动物怎样了
What happened to all the test animals they were using here?
谁知道
Who knows?
也许杀了  也许放了
Maybe destroyed. Maybe set free.
这里见证了许多悲伤的故事
These walls have many sad stories to tell.
这些傻瓜是来偷铜和钛的
These fools, they come here to steal copper and titanium.
他已经死了
He's already dead.
我昨天看他还活着呢
Hmmm, he was alive when I found him yesterday.
你怎么不救他
Why didn't you help him?
这么多灌多了伏特加就来偷东西的白痴
I can't be responsible for every vodka-soaked idiot
我可照顾不过来
who comes in here to steal.
再说了  他已经救不过来了
Besides, he was already too far gone.
他死了就对我没用了
He's of no use to me dead.
但你还是要付我钱  朋友
But you'll still pay me, my friend.
帮我把他翻过来
Help me turn him over.
你干什么
What are you doing?!
搞科研
Science.
这里是僵尸大灾变  您需要转接哪位
Zombie apocalypse, how may I direct your call?
咬痕研究所吗
Operation Bite Mark?
活着的都在呢  我是多克
Uh, yeah, what's left of us. This is Doc speaking.
很好  你们还在一起吗
Excellent. Are you all still together?
都在都在  很高兴听到你的声音
Correctomundo. Nice to hear your voice.
说吧  前方还有什么鬼
So what fresh hell awaits us?
根据被我黑进去的研究所手册的说法
According to the operations manual I've hacked into,
你们都需要进行消毒
you're going to need to go through decontamination.
真是太好了
Well that sounds great to me
因为我老久都没好好洗个澡了  大概从
cuz I ain't had a decent shower since, let's see,
纽约之后就没洗过
New York.
严格来讲不算是洗澡
Well it's not exactly a shower.
但最最重要的是这一点
But here's the most important thing.
你们回到外界之前  千万务必
It is imperative that you decontaminate again
要再消毒一次
before going back to the surface.
因为这个实验室的检疫隔离等级是
This lab is equipped with Defcon One level
一级戒备
quarantine assurance.
Defcon One?
那不是个跟核大战有关的词吗
Well isn't that some kind of nuclear term?
一旦检疫隔离系统被突破
In the event of the breach of the quarantine system,
该实验室将受到战术核武器打击
the lab is targeted to be incinerated
以确保完全摧毁
by a tactical nuclear weapon.
我真是一点都不吃惊啊
What am I not surprised?
另外关于这个消毒
And there's one other thing
还有一点你们得知道一下
about the decontamination process you need to know.
是吗  哪一点
Yeah, what's that?
非得全裸吗
Naked?
这是他原话
That's what he said.
全裸
Naked.
而且我们还得把衣服什么的
And then we got to put all our clothes and stuff
全都放进这个溜槽里
in this chute here to get decontaminated with some
拿液氮消毒
liquid nitrogen.
那我们等什么呢
So what are we waiting for?
等你们转过脸去
For y'all to turn around.
不准偷看姐
And no peeking.
眼睛朝前看  小万万
Eyes up front, young man.
对不起  不好意思
Sorry. Sorry.
卡桑德拉  你还好吧
Cassandra, you okay?
我感觉我快要晕倒了
I feel like I'm gonna pass out.
你再撑一下  多克  接下来做什么
You hang in there. Doc, what now?
哦  接下来戴上这个
Oh, we got to put these on.
然后...  然后就要
And...and then you got to
按下那个写着消毒字样的按键
hit that button marked decontamination
按键就在你面前  一万
in front of you, 10K.
摩菲
Murphy.
你的伤疤
Your scars.
看起来好像扩散了
It looks like it's spreading.
我正想找莫奇医生算算这笔账呢
That's what I wanted to talk to Doctor Merch about.
戴好你的护目镜  别盯着我看
Well put your goggles on and quit staring.
我又不是什么大象人
I'm not the goddamn elephant man.
我是人类
I'm a human being.
算是吧
Sort of.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
按吧
Just do it.
不好  我的小弟弟好像被灼伤了
Man, I think I fried my gonads.
我应该给它涂点防晒霜的
I shoulda used sunscreen on my junk.
你没事吧
You're okay.
我觉得我不能继续走了
I don't think I can go much further.
我来照顾她
I've got her.
实在不行的话我抱着她走
I'll carry her if I have to.
好吧  行
Okay. Sure.
看见什么了吗
Can you see anything?
等会  里面太黑了
Hold on, little too dark.
注意
里面有一些应急灯样的东西在闪
There's some kind of emergency lights flashing.
兄弟  这儿写着隔离呢
Dude, it says quarantine.
我们就不能信他们一回吗
Can't we just believe them?
你怎么回事  傻了吗
What are you, high?
我们已经被感染了  你忘了吗
We're infected already, remember?
这地方到底是干什么用的
What is this place?
这里不是医院  这简直就是个魔窟
This isn't a hospital. It's a goddamn hall of horrors.
嘿  快看
Hey, look.
我的神呐
Oh my God.
我希望上帝不知道这些事
I hope God doesn't know about this.
因为他要是知道的话...
Cuz if he does...
我们应该给她施以仁慈
We should give her mercy.
不行  要是打开这扇门
No. If we open this door,
苍蝇就会飞出来吃我们的
them flies are gonna be feeding on us.
到这儿来
Over here.
这里面的不见了  门是开着的
This one's gone. The door's open.
它是什么呢
What was it?
你应该问
Better question is
它去哪里了
where'd it go?
管它是什么玩意儿  它还在这儿
Well whatever it is, it's still here.
我靠不是吧...
Shut the...
还有一个
There's another one.
摩菲  快跟他们吐槽  就...  你擅长的那个
Murphy. Go talk to them. Do...do that thing you do.
伙计们
Guys.
它们不是普通的僵尸
These aren't regular zombies.
好像是一种变异僵尸
They're some kind of mutant thing.
我觉得它们貌似不喜欢我呀
I don't think they like me!
去找莫奇吧
Let's go find Merch.
找到莫奇之后他会做什么呢
What's he gonna do when he catches up to Merch?
我不知道  幸好我不是莫奇
I dunno, but I'm glad I'm not her.
做好一切准备  走吧
Be ready for anything. Let's go.
海地  太子港  疫情爆发前一年
这就是我之前跟你说的那位病人
This is the patient I was telling you about.
他这种状态持续多久了
How long has he been like this?
地震之后开始  大概...
Since the earthquake. Almost...
到目前为止七年了
seven years now.
他被埋在废墟底下二十一天之后存活下来
He was buried under rubble for 21 days and survived,
但被救出来后就一直是这种状态
but has been in this state since his rescue.
他对外界有任何反应吗
Is he responsive at all?
有一种非常奇怪的反应
In a strange way.
请坐起来  好吗
Can you sit up, please?
他能对命令做出反应
He responds to commands
但是对周围环境似乎完全没有意识
but seems to be completely unaware of his surroundings
而且没有任何自主意志
and has no will of his own.
他说过话吗
Has he ever spoken?
没有
No.
有员工戏称他为僵尸
The staff has nicknamed him "The zombie."
真的吗
Really?
太迷人了
Fascinating.
您不介意我离开一会吧
If you'll excuse me a minute.
当然
Of course.
可以把胳膊放下了
You can lower your arm.
转过来看着我
Turn toward me.
躺回去
Lie back down.
我坚持不住了
I can't do it.
停
Stop.
我能带你一起走
I can carry you.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
大家都会被我拖累死的
I'm gonna get us all killed.
求你了
Please,
汤米
Tommy.
好吧
Okay.
别告诉其他人我的名字  可以吗
Just don't tell anybody my name, all right?
我不会说的
I won't.
她已经...
Is she...?
她还活着
She's still alive.
发生了什么
What happened?
你在这里休息一下
You can stay here and get some rest.
我们会回来接你的
And we'll come back for you.
听着
Look.
自纽约起  我一直留着这宝贝
I've been saving this special since New York.
我要你拿着它
I want you to have it.
只是以防万一
Just in case.
谢谢你  沃伦
Thank you, Warren.
你懂的
You got it.
你坚持住  亲爱的
You hang in there, darlin'.
我们会找到抗生素
We're gonna find you some antibiotics,
很快就能把你治好
and we're gonna get you straightened out in no time.
谢谢你  汤米
Thank you, Tommy.
伙计们
Guys,
快过来
come on.
我好像发现了什么
I think I found something.
她能挺过去吗
Is she gonna make it?
你可能得跟她道别了
You might want to say your goodbyes.
我们走吧
Let's go.
快看看这个
Check this out.
血迹一直延续到这里
This trail of gore leads to here.
生物封存室
Biocontainment.
这鬼地方还能再吓人点吗
Could this place get any creepier?
是啊
Yes.
天啊
Oh my God.
它还活着呢
It's alive.
这就是莫奇医生吗
Is that Doctor Merch?
不是
No.
是另一个人
Somebody else.
就是录像里的那个技术员
It's the lab tech in the video.
他想让我们看点东西
He wants us to watch something.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this to me?
这是为你好  布伦登
It's for your own good, Brendon.
你已经对病毒有反应了
You've started to react to the virus.
别给我注射你给猴子们打的鬼东西
Don't give me that shit you've been giving the monkeys.
我见识过它的副作用
I've seen the side effects.
我们不能冒险  病毒已经传染给人类了
We can't take the chance the virus has jumped to humans.
你会是疫苗的首例人体试验者
You'll be the first human trial of the vaccine.
我们不能再等了
We can't wait any longer.
我会怎样
What's gonna happen to me?
我们也不知道
We don't know.
按住他
Hold him down.
Hold him down!
按住了
Hold him still.
把摄影机关掉
And turn off that camera.
一定是疫苗起作用了
The vaccine must have worked.
没有使他变成僵尸
Kept him from turning zombie.
但也没能让他解脱
But it won't let him die.
莫奇把你变成这样的吗
Did Merch do this to you?
他想要说点什么
He's trying to say something.
杀了我
Kill me.
我们快离开这鬼地方
We're getting the hell out of here.
这里还有其他人
You've got company.
好像是莫奇医生和两名士兵朝你们这来了
Looks like Doctor Merch and two soldiers headed your way.
他们马上就到
They should be there any second.
当心
Heads up.
莫奇医生
Doctor Merch.
我们又见面了
We meet again.
莫奇医生没有活下来
Doctor Merch didn't make it.
我是她的上司  库尔茨医生
I'm her boss, Doctor Kurtz.
我是来此协助您拯救全人类的
I'm here to help you save mankind.
库尔茨医生
Doctor Kurtz.
库尔茨医生  查找库尔茨医生
Doctor Kurtz. Paging Doctor Kurtz.
瞧瞧这简历  太牛了
Wow. Look at that resume?
团队领导人  艾滋病毒疫苗专利持有人
Team leader, patent holder, HIV vaccine.
埃博拉病毒二代疫苗专利持有人
Patent holder, Ebola 2.0 vaccine.
因彻底根除SARS病毒而诺贝尔奖
Nobel Prize. Credited with eradication of SARS.
这就是传说中的"别人家的孩子"啊
Wow. Somebody made their mama proud.
这不是库尔茨医生呀
That's not Doctor Kurtz.
那这人到底是谁
Who the hell is this?
我们花了很大力气去找你  摩菲先生
We've gone to a great deal of effort to find you, Mr. Murphy.
我和小伙伴来了一趟公路旅行而已
I've been on a little road trip.
你的旅程到此结束  你安全了
Well your journey ends here. You're safe now.
你的朋友会因勇气与全力相助
And your friends are to be commended for their
得以表彰
bravery and commitment.
整个国家乃至全人类都欠你们一份恩情
Your country, all mankind, owes you a great deal.
你们会把他怎么样
What's going to happen to him?
我们会把他带到加利福尼亚州的实验室
Well we'll take him the rest of the way to the lab in California
我们会测定他的基因序列
where we'll sequence his genes
克隆他血液里的抗体
and clone the antibodies in his blood.
但愿
Then with any luck,
我们能够制出这种使他存活的疫苗
we'll be able to recreate the vaccine that's keeping him alive.
库里安医生
Doctor... Kurian?
库里安医生  你又是何方人物
Who are you Doctor Kurian?
编码改写你个鬼
Redacted my ass.
如果我不想做你的实验小白鼠呢
What if I don't want to be your guinea pig?
那你就会跟布伦登·道尔一个下场
Well then you'll eventually wind up just like Brendon Doyle,
那边那位首例感染者
Patient Zero over there.
说起这个
Speaking of which,
给那位苟延残喘的怪物"施以仁慈"吧
someone should really give that poor creature mercy.
我来吧
I'll do it.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
对于你的遭遇  我很抱歉
I'm sorry about all of it.
不要
Don't
相信
trust
他
him.
千万...别信他
Don't...trust...him.
我仁慈地结束你的生命
I give you mercy.
我不会跟你走
I'm not going.
摩菲
Murphy.
我们此行的目的就在于此
This is why we came this far.
我凭什么相信你说的每一句话
Explain to me again why I should believe anything you say.
首先  你别无选择
Let's start with you have no choice.
你干什么
What are you doing?
以防万一
Just a precaution.
大家稍安勿躁
Now just hold on a minute.
没必要动手  他只是紧张而已
Ain't no reason to jump bad. He's just nervous.
是吧  摩菲
Right, Murphy?
他其实是个很有公德心的人
He's actually very civic minded.
不
No!
因向朝鲜  伊朗  伊拉克出售生化武器技术
Wanted by Interpol for selling bio weapon technology
而被国际刑警通缉
to North Korea, Iran, Iraq.
因涉嫌开发争议性的催眠药接受调查
Under investigation for the development of battlefield hypnotics.
这家伙根本没有制造出疫苗
This guy didn't create the vaccine.
我的天  我把他们带进陷阱里去了
Oh my God, I've lead them into a trap.
三角洲X光小队  收到请回复
Delta-Xray-Delta! Do you copy?
三角洲X光小队  请回答
Delta-Xray-Delta! Come in!
我的天  我的神  三角洲X光小队请回复
Oh my God! Oh my God! Delta-Xray-Delta! Do you copy?
-三角洲X光小队  -真的没必要这样
- Delta-Xray-Delta! - Really, this is so unnecessary.
没人会伤害你  摩菲先生
No one's going to harm you, Mr. Murphy.
-三角洲X光小队  -而正相反
- Delta-Xray-Delta! - Quite the opposite.
收到请回复
Do you copy?
杀死那个医生
Kill the doctor.
你们得杀了那个医生
You have to kill the doctor.
一个僵尸而已
Just a zombie.
给它施以仁慈以免招来更多僵尸
Give it mercy so it won't attract more.
僵尸不会开门  对吧
Zombies can't open doors, can they?
别开枪
Don't shoot.
她是个僵尸
She's a zombie.
对她施以仁慈
Mercy her.
我没死
I'm not dead.
杀了他
Kill him.
摩菲  等一下
Murphy, wait!
多克
Doc!
Doc.
多克
喂喂喂喂  看着我
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Look at me.
看着我
Look at me.
摩菲
Murphy!
你
You.
你设计我  你这混蛋
You set me up, you bastard.
-你设计我们所有人  -没有  我没有
- You set us all up! - No! No, I didn't.
我不知道会发生这样的事  我发誓
I had no idea this was gonna happen. I swear.
-你要相信我  -不  我不相信
- You have to believe me. - No, I don't!
我再也不会相信任何人说的话
I don't have to believe anything anyone says ever again!
尤其是你
Especially you!
你必须听我说
You have got to listen to me.
你被病毒感染了
You're infected with the virus.
如果你在病毒
If you attempt to exit the lab
没被清除前离开实验室
without going through decontamination,
就会触动安全装置
you're gonna set off the fail safe.
我才不在乎
And why should I care?
该死  摩菲  听着
Damn it, Murphy! Listen!
我失去了一切
I lost everything!
包括我自己
Including myself!
摩菲
Murphy.
北美防空部会发射战术核武器
A tactical nuclear weapon will be launched from NORAD
焚毁实验室
to incinerate the lab.
如果你离开  你会害死那里的人
If you go up, you will kill everyone there,
包括沃伦  多克  还有其他人
including Warren, Doc, and the others.
听到我说的话吗
Do you read me?
摩菲  听到我说的话吗
Murphy, do you read me?
摩菲
Murphy!
摩菲  我没有设计你  听到了吗
Murphy! I did not set you up. Do you copy?
摩菲
Murphy!
安全装置启动
Fail safe activated.
安全装置已启动
剩余七分钟爆炸
Seven minutes to detonation.
快醒来  多克
Come on, Doc.
多克
Doc.
醒醒  多克
Get up, Doc.
快醒来  多克
Come on, Doc.
剩余六分钟爆炸
Six minutes to detonation.
醒醒  多克
Wake up, Doc.
快醒来  多克
Come on Doc.
快离开这里
Get out of here!
-快离开这里  -醒醒  多克
- Get out of here! - Wake up, Doc.
-现在就离开  -醒醒  多克
- Now! - Wake up, Doc.
现在就离开这里
Get out of here now!
剩余五分钟爆炸
Five minutes to detonation.
快点
Come on.
到底发生什么事了
What the hell is happening?
我勒个去
Holy crap.
肯定是触发了第三类攻击武器的发射
They must be third strike weapons on a dead man switch.
我们到底是怎么了
What is wrong with us?
剩余四分钟爆炸
Four minutes to detonation.
你要去哪里
Where are you headed?
你去开门
Get the door.
剩余三分钟爆炸
Three minutes to detonation.
看
Look.
这是什么
What is it?
摩菲就留下这个吗
Is that all that's left of Murphy?
这是他的皮肤
It's his skin.
他把他的皮肤扒下来了
He shed his skin.
收好
Keep it.
拿去做些很赞的靴子
Make some awesome boots out of that.
摩菲在哪里
Where's Murphy?
货车在哪里
Where's the van?
摩菲开走了
Murphy.
快  我们坐这辆车离开
Come on, let's take this.
快看
Look.
我们快离开
Let's go.
卡桑德拉怎么办
Cassandra?
天呐  我真讨厌末世
God, I hate the apocalypse.
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译 米小勒   玛莎   CS小明漫画家   小奶   章鱼
翻译 我叫魏碧慧   蔡茸茸   S很爱笑   迷失_绽放
时间轴   SumenQ   安妮   太太乐叽叽     后期   一只PPT
校对   米小勒       总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
第一季 第十三集[季终]